# Alex Advani

### **Unity Developer**

A determined, passionate developer with experience creating 2D/3D gameplay systems, working with physics, implementing UI and adapting projects for multiple platforms. I have worked with Unity and XNA/MonoGame and am always ready for new challenges.

penguinalex1@msn.com

Warminster, United Kingdom

in linkedin.com/in/alex-advani

07484 869733

alexadvani.github.io

github.com/alexadvani

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## C# Web Developer Clever Digit Media ♂

12/2019 – 12/2019

Melksham, Wiltshire

https://www.clever-digit-media.co.uk/

#### Responsibilities

- Maintained websites hosted by the company.
- Diagnosed problems with websites and automated email server functionality.

# Sales Assistant One Stop Retail Stores

05/2017 - 07/2019

Warminster, Wiltshire

https://www.onestop.co.uk/

### Responsibilities

- Served customers and maintained the store by restocking shelves and tidying.
- Was trusted with counting end of day till floats and closing the store.

### **News Writer**

### Final Fantasy Union

05/2010 - 07/2013

Remote

https://www.finalfantasyunion.com/

### Responsibilities

- Balanced workload of finding stories, writing and sourcing images/videos for a final piece.
   (https://www.finalfantasyunion.com/news/2093/finalfantasy-versus-xiii-might-be-cancelled/)
- Collaborated with other remote team members on current news and discussed the state of site's community.
- Worked with the site editor to plan out the upcoming month, especially near big events (E3, Gamescom, etc)

# **EDUCATION**

# **BSc (Hons) Computer Games Development** University of Bedfordshire

09/2012 - 07/2015

Second Class - Upper Division

### **A Levels**

### Kingdown Community School

09/2010 - 06/2012

### Courses

Maths (A)

- Further Maths (B)
- ICT (Distinction)AS Physics (C)

## **SKILLS**

C# (Unity, XNA / MonoGame)

Web (HTML5, CSS)

XML

JSON

Version Control (Github, TortoiseSVN)

Time Management (Trello, Notepad)

Collaboration (Slack, Zoom)

## **KEY PROJECTS**

### Cyberangel: Last Hope <a> В</a>

- Sole Developer
- A Platformer with a focus on fast movement and intense action.
- Includes a fully featured movement system, gunplay and a customisable loadout. (4 weapons)
- Fully featured demo with 4 stages featuring a tutorial, an area to explore all of the player's movement abilities and a test mission with a time trial and score challenge with combo functionality.
- Features 2D skeleton animation, a dynamic 2D camera, controller support with rumble, remappable controls for all control methods, object pooling and a save system.

### Digital Desperado 🗷

- Programmer (Level Generation) as part of a small team of four.
- A quick level-based FPS with a bold art style, made as part of my 3rd year studies at University.
- Developed level generation feature which utilises XML files to create level objects as well as store a leaderboard for times made on that level

### Ascender 🗷

- Gameplay Programmer as part of a team of five.
- A small, slow-paced deliberate Platformer and a light mechanic, made for Global Game Jam 2014.
- Programmed a Platformer Controller from scratch using Unity's 2D physics system in 48 hours.
- Collaborated with an artist to implement character animation.

# **INTERESTS**

Gaming (Particularly Platformers, FPS's and RPGs)

Movies

Books

Drawing & Digital Art

Walking (Around parks and the neighbourhood, anywhere that gives me a clear space to think)